Jaseel P V

Web developer professional with 4+ years of experience writing, reviewing and fixing code aiming for a position with a company where I can contribute to a dynamic and growing IT team.

Bangalore, India +91 97466 64696 jaseelbavu@gmail.com https://jaseel.in

EXPERIENCE

High Root Ventures LLP - Kerala, India — *Co-founder/Web Developer*

DECEMBER 2021 - PRESENT

- Project planning and implementation for an ecommerce brand ekdhara
- Developed and maintained new modules for the website.
- API integration for delhivery.
- Version control system for tracking and managing changes to the project codes.

Al Zarooni Group of Companies - Dubai, UAE — *Laravel Developer*

JANUARY 2021 - MARCH 2021

- Involved in optimizing API code.
- Developed modules for easy accountability features.

Palmate Solutions - Bangalore, India — Web Developer

SEPTEMBER 2019 - DECEMBER 2020

- Lead the team to migrate existing and new projects to Laravel framework.
- Providing guidance to the team to learn Laravel framework and with their works.
- Involved in project development from scratch to deployment.
- Version control system for tracking and managing changes to the project codes.
- Hands-on experience with API like REST API, payment API and Google API.

Examsummary - Kochi, India — *Co-founder/Web Developer*

JANUARY 2016 - MAY 2017 (NASSCOM 10,000 Startups Incubated Company, Infopark)

- Work closely with other co-founders about the product development and implementation.
- Conducted target market research to scope out industry competition and identify advantageous trends.
- Help ensure students have a seamless experience across subjects and grade levels.
- Create and maintain software documentation.

SKILLS

PHP, Laravel, MySQL, Vue.js, Bootstrap, Linux, Rest API, SQL, Javascript, CSS, JQuery, Git

Work Links

Graduate Guru - Elearning platform

https://graduateguru.in/

Antarrashtriya - Ecommerce platform

https://antarrashtriva.in/

Ekdhara - Ecommerce platform

http://ekdhara.com/

Open source contribution

https://github.com/bagisto/bagisto/commits?author=jaseelbavu

LANGUAGES

English, Malayalam

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Nationality: Indian
Date of Birth: 09/11/1995

EDUCATION

The Oxford College of Engineering - Bangalore, India — *Master of Computer Application*

AUGUST 2017 - JULY 2019

Assabah Arts And Science College - Changaramkulam, India — Bachelor of Computer Application

AUGUST 2013 - MAY 2016